HIRA FATIMA

SUMMARY

I am Final year Computer Science student. If everything goes well I'll be a CS graduate in the next 5 months. I am currently working on my Final Year Project which is based on Cognition in machines. To achieve this, I've been working on Deep Learning and Neural networks for the past 5 months. Besides that, I am an SEO Expert. I work on On-page, Off-page, and Technical SEO. I've completed a five-course specialization in SEO from UC, Davis. Apart from what I do professionally, I love bullet journaling and I've started a blog for my hobby.

CONTACT

- contact@hirafs.me
- +92 320 2115433
- in linkedin.com/in/hirafs
- www.hirafs.me
- github.com/hirafs

EDUCATION

2017 - 2021 • Shaheed Zulfiqar Ali Bhutto Institute of Science and Technology (SZABIST)

BS Computer Science

EXPERIENCE

Upwork | May 2019 - Present

Freelance SEO Writer

- Worked for over 18 clients and maintained 80% good Job Success Score.
- My work included writing SEO optimized articles/blogs for different websites,
- Maintained the rankings and take care of the technical SEO.

TeacherOn | Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

Programming tutor

• Taught C++, C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Technical SEO to different students from all over the world on Zoom and Google meet.

Newton Day Ltd | Oct 2020 - Dec 2020

Search Engine Optimization Manager

- Managed technical SEO, Google Analytics, and content of 6 UK-based websites.
- My job included On-page, off-page, technical SEO along with social media, audience analysis, website monitoring and user analysis.

Final Choice E-Commerce | Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

Search Engine Optimization Specialist

- Performed keyword research including discovery and expansion of keyword opportunities and implemented content recommendations for organic SEO success.
- Prepared monthly reports to analyze the performance and observe the improvments.

VIRTUAL EXPERIENCE PROGRAMS

JPMorgan Chase & Co. on Forage | Dec 2020 - Feb 2021

Software Engineering Virtual Experience Program participant

The tasks included:

- Interface with a stock price data feed using JPMorgan Chase frameworks and tools and also displaying data visually for traders.
- In addition to this, we experienced using "Perspective JP Morgan's Data Visualization software" on our local machines.

Microsoft | July 2020

Engineering: Undergraduate & Masters Asia Virtual Experience Program participant

- Learnt about Microsoft's values, using SMART goals to meet our career goals, explored Microsoft's cultural transformation, learnt about Microsoft's Four Solutions that enable digital transformation.
- Other activities include; learning about Azure, importance of personal branding, and professional meetings.

VOLUNTEER WORK

Robinhood Army | Jan 2017 - Feb 2017

Social work

• Collected surplus food from the restaurants and distributed it among the people living in the slum areas.

Sindh Institute of Urology and Transplant (SIUT) | Jan 2016 - Feb 2016

Social work

• Assisted patients to find the wards, helped them in collecting samples and reading prescriptions, maintained their records etc.

The Kidney Center | Feb 2015 - March 2015

Volunteer

• Assisted patients to find the wards, helped them in collecting samples and reading prescriptions, maintained their records etc.

The Citizens Foundation (TCF) | June 2014 - July 2014

Community Service

• Helped underprivileged children learn, write, and speak English along with Math, drama, sports and other fun activities.

World Wide Fund for Nature (WWF) | June 2014 -July 2014

Community Service

· Awareness about the environmental crisis, beach cleaning and other fun activities.

SKILLS

Programming languages

- C | C# | C++ | Java
- Python
- HTML | CSS
- JavaScript
- Node JS
- React
- jQuery
- React Native

Tools and technologies

- Eclipse
- VMWare
- IntelliJ Idea
- Code Blocks
- NetBeans,
- MS Office (Excel, Word, Access)
- Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- GIT
- WordPress

CERTIFICATIONS

- Transfer learning for NLP with Tensor flow hub
 ISSUED BY COURSERA PROJECT NETWORK [FEB]
 - Introduction to Python

 ISSUED BY DATA CAMP [JAN]
- Artificial Intelligence for everyone
 ISSUED BY DEEPLEARNING.AI ON COURSERA [SEP]
 - Git + GitHub for open source collaboration

 ISSUED BY COURSERA PROJECT NETWORK [AUG]

Other skills

- On-page SEO
- · Off-page SEO
- · Technical SEO
- · Machine learning
- Deep Learning
- Content Writing
- Copywriting
- Digital marketing

Soft skills

- Problem-solving
- Communication
- Perseverance
- Time management
- Organizational
- Stress management
- Openness to criticism

• SEARCH ENGINE OPTIMIZATION SPECIALIZATION

ISSUED BY UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, DAVIS [AUG]

The specialization included the following courses:

- 1. Introduction to Search Engine Optimization [MARCH]
- 2. Search Engine Optimization Fundamentals [JUNE]
- 3. Optimizing a Website for Search [JULY]
- 4. Advanced Content and Social Tactics to Optimize SEO [AUG]
- 5. Website Optimization Client Report Project [AUG]
- How to write and publish a scientific paper (Project-Centered Course)

 ISSUED BY ÉCOLE POLYTECHNIQUE [APRIL]
- JSON Data

 ISSUED BY STANFORD ONLINE [JAN]
- Design and prototype in Adobe XD
 ISSUED BY UDEMY [JAN]
- 2019 Digital skills Social media
 ISSUED BY FUTURE LEARN [JAN]
 - Introduction to Typography
 ISSUED BY CALIFORNIA INSTITUTE OF THE ARTS [JAN]
- Fundamentals of Graphic Design
 ISSUED BY CALIFORNIA INSTITUTE OF THE ARTS [NOV]
 - Grammar and punctuation
 ISSUED BY COURSERA [AUG]
- Increase your influence online ISSUED BY UDEMY [OCT]
 - Effective time management ISSUED BY UDEMY [OCT]